<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lukas Scheucher</title><link>https://scheuclu.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Lukas Scheucher</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:01:17 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scheuclu.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mandelbrot images</title><link>https://scheuclu.github.io/posts/mandelbrot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 15:01:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://scheuclu.github.io/posts/mandelbrot/</guid><description>Github Deployed
The mandelbrot explorer Overview The goal of this project was to implement an interactive explorer for the mandelbrot set.
It&amp;rsquo;s definition is very simple. A complex number c is considered to be in the mandelbrot set if the iteration
$$\forall c \in \mathbb{C}: \\ ~ \\ z_{0}=0 \\ z_{i+1}=z_{i}^2+c$$
converges to a stationary value. Coloring all the convergent points, gives a picture like this
If instead, the above equation diverges, we can color that point based on how fast it diverges.</description></item><item><title>Implementing a calculator from scratch</title><link>https://scheuclu.github.io/posts/overkill_calculator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 15:01:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://scheuclu.github.io/posts/overkill_calculator/</guid><description>Github Deployed
The Overkill calculator The goal of this project was to implement a calculator from scratch. Notably, I wanted to do it without the use of any sophisticated libraries.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the feature specification:
Infix and Reverse Polish notation are supported. Parentheses are supported. Basic arithmatic as well as trigonometric functions are supported. Supports basic constants such as Eulers number or Pi. The calculator can solve for one unknown in a linear equation.</description></item><item><title>Sudoku Solver</title><link>https://scheuclu.github.io/posts/sudoko_solver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 15:01:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://scheuclu.github.io/posts/sudoko_solver/</guid><description>Github Deployed
Sudoku Solver You can use the Sudoku Solver whenever you are stuck on a puzzle.
I support both manual input as well as input via camera or webcam.
Note At the moment, the camera input is buggy, so you probably have to correct the results manually.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a little demo of how it works.
Overview The solver consists of the following step
Read the image from webcam Identify the sudoku grid using classical computer vision Dewarp the grid to rectangular format Split the rectangle into 9x9 subimages Identify the content of eacht subimage Brute Force a solution</description></item><item><title>Why I quit my job at Google</title><link>https://scheuclu.github.io/posts/why_quit_google/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 15:01:17 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://scheuclu.github.io/posts/why_quit_google/</guid><description>This blog posts describes my motivation for quitting my job at Google. I&amp;rsquo;ve been asked about this many times and also have a lot of former colleagues in the same dilemma, so maybe it is of help to somebody.
Table Of Contents First things first How I got the job Why I took the job The positives Professionalism Perks The negatives Middle management Politics Lack of personal development Working in silos Office locations First things first To begin with, I do want to state that this is an absolute first world issue.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://scheuclu.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scheuclu.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Please fill the form below if you&amp;rsquo;d like to get in touch.
Your Name Email Address An email address is required. Message</description></item><item><title>CV</title><link>https://scheuclu.github.io/cv/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://scheuclu.github.io/cv/</guid><description>Please download my CV here.</description></item></channel></rss>